Postcards
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Postcards, 2.1.7
  - United States of America (Colorado), undated; 7 (Box 1601)
    - Verso: THE GOLD KING AND MOLLY KATHLEEN MINES both producers. Here in Povery Gulch, Bob Womack discovered the strike in 1891 that made Cripple Creek. Within ten years there were over fifty millionaires in the district.], 18-verso
    - [Cripple Creek Museum], 19
    - Verso: THE CRIPPLE CREEK FREE MUSEUM. The old Colorado Midland Depot was purchsed recently by two interested citizens who then dontated it to the city. It was built about 1896 and now houses priceless relics of a colorful and historic past., 19-verso
    - [Bennett Avenue in Cripple Creek, Colorado], 20
    - Verso: BENNETT AVENUE IN CRIPPLE CREEK, COLORADO. Here have trod some of the world's most famous characters, from royalty to gamblers. Here today surges a mass of vacationing America, expecting and getting the welcome hand of a friendly, modern, city., 20-verso
    - [Carlton Mill], 21
    - Verso: CARLTON MILL where the romantic past of the burro, the mule skinner and ore wagons is not forgotten. Today, instead of weary miles to the smelter, the precious minerals are processed in this modern plant. Since 1951 over 5 millions dollars' worth of gold bricks have been made here., 21-verso
    - [Gold Mines], 22
    - Verso: THE AJAX, STRATTON'S FAMOUS INDEPENDENCE, PORTLAND NO. 1 AND PORTLAND NO. 2 four of the largest producing gold mines in the world and still going strong. There are near Victor, Colorado, at the eastern end of the district.], 22-verso
    - [Victor, Colorado], 23
    - Verso: VICTOR, COLORADO the other twin capital of the fabulous Cripple Creek mining district. This end of the camp with the bigger, deeper, and richer mines, produced and is still producing the lion's share of Colorado's gold., 23-verso
    - Back inside Cover of booklet that includes postcards 16-23, 24
    - Back outside Cover of booklet that includes postcards 16-23, 25
  - United States of America (Victor, Colorado), undated; 8 (Box 1601)
    - [View from the top of Mt. Pisgah], 1
    - Verso: View from the top of Mt. Pisgah - Cripple Creek, Colorado. The only perfect 360 degree panoramic view in the world reached by cars today. Longest view of the Continental Divide.], 1-verso
    - [Panorama of Victor, Colorado], 2
    - Verso: Panorama of Victor, Colorado, 2-verso
    - [Victor, Colorado], 3
    - Verso: Looking down on Victor, Colorado in the Cripple Creek mining district, the greatest gold camp in the world. On highway Colorado 67 at the head of the beautiful Phantom Canon., 3-verso
    - [Panorama of Victor, Colorado], 4
    - Verso: Panorama of Victor, Colorado, 4-verso
    - Victor, Colorado - "The city of mines" (early 1900's), 5
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 5-verso
    - Victor, Colorado - "The city of mines" (Early 1900's), 6
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 6-verso
    - Lowell Thomas Boyhood Home Museum, 7
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas's boyhood home in Victor, Colorado., 7-verso
    - Lowell Thomas Boyhood Home Museum, 8
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas's boyhood home in Victor, Colorado., 8-verso
    - [Victor, Colorado], 9
    - Verso: Looking down on Victor, Colorado in the Cripple Creek mining district, the greatest gold camp in the world. On highway Colorado 67 at the head of the beautiful Phantom Canon., 9-verso
    - [Victor, Colorado], 10
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 10-verso
    - Lowell Thomas Boyhood - Home - Museum -Tearoom, Free, Welcome, 11
    - Verso: BOYHOOD HOME OF LOWELL THOMAS. Now a museum of His momento at Victor, Colorado., 11-verso
    - [Victor, Colorado], 12
    - Verso: The historical mining town of Victor, Colorado. The town of Victor is still an active mining center and a growing recreational area., 12-verso
    - [Cooper Airship Co. Cripple Creek, Colorado], 13
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 13-verso
    - Vicroy Ave., Victor Colo. [Colorado], 14
    - Verso: Aug. [August] 21, 1941. Victor Drug Store:-Came up the Corley Road. Going back to the highway. Thinking of the trip Harry Fran [?] and I had [?] here. The country is so green and [?]-Sister [?]. Addressed to Mr. and Mrs. H.G. Thomas, 1113 Fith Ave. Asbury Park, New Jersey., 14-verso
    - [Copper Airship Co., Cripple Creek, Colorado], 15
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 15-verso
    - Victor High School, Victor, Colorado, 16
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 16-verso
    - [Garfield School in Victor, Colorado], 17
    - Verso: Garfield School, attended by LT [Lowell Thomas]. Grammar school, Victor Colo. [Colorado]. Christmas greetings to Lizzie and Sanford., 17-verso
    - Third Street, Victor, Colorado, 18
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 18-verso
    - Birdseye view Victor Colo. [Colorado], 19
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 19-verso
    - North third street and battle mountain, Victor, Colo.[Colorado], 20
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 20-verso
  - United States of America (Connecticut), undated; 9 (Box 1601)
    - [Ragmont Inn Sailsbury, CT], 1
    - Verso: Ragmont Inn Sailsbury, Connecticut. Photograph by Firuski, 1-verso
    - [Ragmont Inn Sailsbury, CT], 2
    - Verso: Ragmont Inn Sailsbury, Connecticut. Photograph by Firuski, 2-verso
  - United States of America (Florida), undated; 10 (Box 1601)
    - Exclusive Bath and Tennis Club, Palm Beach, Fla. [Florida], 1
    - Verso: This exclusive Bath and Tennis Club is the rendezvous of society for its winter ocean and pool bathing, sun tanning, tennis, afternoon teas, and dancing parties., 1-verso
    - The Princess Issena Hotel Inn and Cottages - Daytona Beach, Florida, 2
    - Verso: The Princess Issena, A Sheraton Hotel, Daytona Beach Florida. John E. Leonard, General Manager. Located in a private park of five acres, two blocks from the ocean--Private access to "World's Most Famous Beach." Golf, tennis, riding and all outdoor sports., 2-verso
    - Royal Palm Way, Palm Beach, Fla. [Florida], 3
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 3-verso
    - Royal Palm Way, Palm Beach Fla. [Florida], 4
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 4-verso
    - [The "Singing Tower", from the North Lake Wales, Florida], 5
    - Verso: The "Singing Tower" from the North Lake Wales, Florida, 5-verso
    - ["The Singing Tower" from Sanctuary Lake, Lake Wales, Florida], 6
    - Verso: "The Singing Tower" from Sanctuary Lake, Lake Wales, Florida, 6-verso
    - ["The Singing Tower", Lake Wales, Florida], 7
    - Verso: "The Singing Tower" Lake Wales, Florida, 7-verso
    - ["The Singing Tower", Lake Wales, Florida], 8
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 8-verso
    - Royal Poinciana Tree, Miami Florida, 9
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 9-verso
    - Everglades Club, Palm Beach, Florida, 10
    - Verso: Everglades Club, located on Worth Avenue, famous shopping district was built several years ago by Paris Singer as a retreat for wounded World War officers. This has been turned into a very swanky club, having its own private golf course, tennis courts, apartments, and stores., 10-verso
    - The Lake Trail, Palm Beach Florida, 11
    - Verso: The Lake Trail, reserved exclusively for the use of pedestrians, bicycles and wheel chairs. Here it passes through the famous Royal Poinciana Gardens where grow countless tropical plants, tagged and identified for the benefit of visitors., 11-verso
    - Cypress Gardens, Singing Tower, 12
    - Verso: Beautiful Cypress Gardens; Famous Singing Tower [Cypress Gardens and Famous Singing Tower driving directions and drescriptions], 12-verso
  - United States of America (St. Augustine, Florida) [Lowell Thomas outside oldest wood schoolhouse], circa 1930s; 11 (Box 1601)
    - Lowell Thomas at the oldest school house. St. Augustine, Florida, 1
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 1-verso
  - United States of America (Illinois), undated; 12 (Box 1601)
    - Scene in Washington Park, Chicago, 1
    - Verso: SCENE IN WASHINGTON PARK, CHICAGO. Washington Park is located on the South side from 51st to 60th Street between Cottage Grove Avenue on the east and South Park Avenue on the west, containing a total area of 371 acres. It contains 7 miles of charming driveways, walks and bridle paths and 23 acres of lagoons. An equestrian statue of Washington is located at the Grand Boulevard and 51st Street entrance. The Administration Building of the South Park System is also located at Washington Park., 1-verso
    - Double deck moto busses on Lincoln Park Drive, Chicago, 2
    - Verso: DOUBLE DECK MOTOR BUSSES ON LINCOLN PARK DRIVE, CHICAGO. The motorbusses start at Devon Ave. and Sheridan Road and go down-town via Sheridan Road, Lincoln Park and Lake Shore Drive, then go around the loop via Michigan Ave., Jackson Blvd., State and Washington Sts. and return to the starting point. The fare is ten cents and it requires about one hour each way to make the trip. The best and least expensive method of seeing Chicago.], 2-verso
    - Double deck moto busses on Lincoln Park Drive, Chicago, 3
    - Verso: DOUBLE DECK MOTOR BUSSES ON LINCOLN PARK DRIVE, CHICAGO. The motorbusses start at Devon Ave. and Sheridan Road and go down-town via Sheridan Road, Lincoln Park and Lake Shore Drive, then go around the loop via Michigan Ave., Jackson Blvd., State and Washington Sts. and return to the starting point. The fare is ten cents and it requires about one hour each way to make the trip. The best and least expensive method of seeing Chicago.], 3-verso
    - Lake Shore Drive, Lincoln Park, Chicago, 4
    - Verso: LAKE SHORE DRIVE, LINCOLN PARK, CHICAGO. Lake Shore Drive extends south along the eatsern part of Lincoln Park paralled to the mile-long lagoon, which contains all kinds of small craft. From the south entrance of the park the Drive skirts the Lake Front and on the left are some of the most beautiful residences in the City. On the right is a shaded bridle path, and beyond a gentle sloping beach with great blocks of granite as a protection from the storm waves.], 4-verso
    - The "Olympian" Famous transcontinental train, 5
    - Verso: Chicago Milwaukee & St. Paul Railway. To Puget-Sound-Electrified. The Chicago, Milwaukee & St. Paul Railway is the shortest line and the scenic route between Chicago and Puget Sound. The Olympian is one of the finest trains in the world], 5-verso
    - Open air observation cars are attached to the "Olympian" during the summer months, 6
    - Verso: Chicago Milwaukee & St. Paul Railway. To Puget Sound- Electrified. The absence of smoke and cinders under electrical operation makes the use of open-air observation cars on the Olympian and enjoyable luxury], 6-verso
    - Dining car service on the "Olympian" is unsurpassed, 7
    - Verso: Chicago Milwaukee & St.Paul Railway. To Puegt Sound-Electric. The dining cars on Olympian are models of dignified simplicity-beautiful in deisgn-elegant in appointment-and provide a service fully up to the standard of excellence for which this railroad is famous], 7-verso
  - United States of America (Maine), circa 1933; 13 (Box 1601)
    - Brinkerhoff Island, Meddybemps, Maine."Pat's summer house", 1
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 1-verso
  - United States of America (Massachusetts), undated; 14 (Box 1601)
    - Hotel Statler, Park Square at Arlington Street, 1
    - Verso: HOTEL: STATLER, BOSTON. 1300 Rooms with Bath and Radio Reception. The largest finest of the Hotels Statler. Located at the heart of uptown Boston; Park Square at Arlington Street. Operated in connection with Hotels Statler, Buffalo, Cleveland, Detroit, St. Louis, Hotel Buffalo, Buffalo, and Hotel Pennsylvania, New York., 1-verso
    - [Looking north from the auditorium tower Northfield School for Girls. East Northfield, Massacusetts], 2
    - Verso: Looking north from the auditorium tower Northfield School for Girls. East Northfield, Massacusetts, 2-verso
    - [Gould Hall, Northfield School for Girls, East Northfield, Massachusetts], 3
    - Verso: Gould Hall, Northfield School for Girls, East Northfield, Mass. [Massachusetts], 3-verso
  - United States of America (Princeton, New Jersey), undated; 15 (Box 1601)
    - Library, Princeton University, Princeton, N.J. [New Jersey], 1
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 1-verso
    - Nassau Street, Princeton N.J. [New Jersey], 2
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 2-verso
    - Graduate College, Princeton University, 3
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 3-verso
    - Nassau Hall, Princeton University., 4
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 4-verso
    - "Westland" the Home of Ex-President Cleaveland, Princeton N.J. [New Jersey], 5
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 5-verso
    - [Henry Van Dyke Residence. Princeton, N.J. [New Jersey], 6
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 6-verso
    - Cleveland Memorial Tower, The Graduate College. Proctor Memorial Hall; Princeton Univeristy, 7
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 7-verso
    - Gymnasium; Princeton Univeristy, 8
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 8-verso
    - Whig and Clio Halls; Princeton University, 9
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 9-verso
    - Proctor Memorial Hall, Graduate College; Princeton University, 10
    - Verso [Blank back of card], 10-verso
  - United States of America (New Mexico), undated; 16 (Box 1601)
    - Oldest house in the U.S., 1
    - Verso: Oldest house in the U.S., Santa Fe, New Mexico. The site of the Santa Fe (City of Holy Faith) was originally and Indian Pueblo. Onate had established his first capital at San Gabriel in 1598; in 1605 this was moved to the present site of Santa Fe, at which place a small Spanish village existed. This old house was one of the early structures of that time., 1-verso
    - Kiva of ancient cliff dwellers, in ceremonial cave, Rito de los Frijoles Canyon, New Mexico, 2
    - Verso: The Kiva or Estufa is a circular underground chamber from ten to forty odd feet in diameter, roofed with large vigas or timbers and covered with saplings and earth. Entrance is gained thru the hatch in the roof by means of a long ladder. An altar, fireplace, sipapu, flue or draft and various niches are essential features of the interior arrangement. The kiva is the ceremonial center of all Indian life and in this underground chamber, all important councils are held, and ceremonies and dances begin and end., 2-verso
    - [Palace of the Governors, Santa Fe, New Mexico], 3
    - Verso: Palace of the Governors, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 3-verso
  - United States of America (New York), undated; 17 (Box 1601)
    - [New York Hospital, New York City], 1
    - Verso: New York Hospital, New York City, 1-verso
    - Grants Tomb, New York, 2
    - Verso: Grant's Tomb. A magnificent mausoleum erected by the City of New York in memory of the famous general in recognitionof his services during the civil war. Here, side by side, lie the remains of Gen. U.S. Grant and his wife. The tomb is visited by tousands daily.], 2-verso
    - Sky Line, New York City, 3
    - Verso: NEW YORK SKYLINE. Showing skyline of Manhatten from Jersey City. Manhatten Island 19.65 square miles, was purchases in 1626 from Indians for about $24.00, land value now $4,020,000,000, total realty value with improvements, is $6,075,000,000, and average of $432,000 per acre. The Island has 2,331,542 inhabitants, the lower end has an office population of 400,000 land there is worth from $200 to $600 per square foot and office space rents at from $1 to $40 per square foot.], 3-verso
    - Baker Court, Conrnell Universoty, Ithaca, N.Y., 4
    - Verso: Baker Court, a part of the Men's Dormitory group at Cornell, which together with others planned for the future, will eventually occupy an area of about fifteen acres.], 4-verso
    - Entrance to Mohonk Lake, Smiley Testimonial Gateway, Mohonk Lake, N.Y, 5
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 5-verso
    - [Lake Mohonk Mountain House, Mohonk Lake, N.Y.], 6
    - Verso: The House from Lake Shore Road with Perch Rock in the foreground, Lake Mohonk Mountain House, Mohonk Lake, N.Y., 6-verso
    - Vanderbilt Mansion, National Historic Site, Hyde Park, N.Y., 7
    - Verso: VANDERBUILT MANSION NATIONAL HISTORIC SITE. Established July 1940 as a Unit of the Historical Site, set aside by the Government for the benefit of the people. Made possible by gift to the Government, by Mrs. Margaret Louise Van Alen. The site comprises 211 acres, beautiful grounds, overlooking the Hudson River, together with the Mansion of the late Frederick W. Vanderbilt.], 7-verso
    - The Franklin D. Roosevelt Memorial Library, Hyde Park, N.Y., 8
    - Verso: THE FRANKLIN D. ROOSEVELT LIBRARY. The Library will serve as a depository for the histoical material, personal papers and books accumulated by Franklin D. Roosevelt during his long service in Public Office. The Library was established as an agency of the U.S. Government by a joint resolution of Congress approved July 18, 1939. The exhibit and museum portions are open to the public Tues. [Tuesday] to Sat. [Saturday] also Sundays and holidays., 8-verso
    - Home of Franklin D. Roosevelt, National Historic Site, Hyde Park, N.Y., 9
    - Verso: A gift to the Government of the United States, pursuant to a Joint Resolution of the Congress of July 18, 1939. The Home of Franklin D. Roosevelt was designated as a National Historic Site on Jan. [January] 15th, 1944, with the members of the Roosevelt Family retaining life interests in the home and grounds included in the gift. After the death of the President, Mrs. Elanor Roosevelt and her children waived their life interests in the estate., 9-verso
    - Willard Straight Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y., 10
    - Verso: Willard Straight Hall, built as a memorial to a former Cornellian, is the Student Club House. It contains a library, several reading and club rooms, a theater, three restaurants and the various undergraduate organization offices., 10-verso
    - Taughannock Falls, In the Finger Lakes region of central New York, 11
    - Verso: Taughannock Falls, the highest falls east of the Rocky Mts. [Mountains], in Taughannock State Park, located on Cayuga Lake near Ithaca, in the Finger Lakes Region of Central New York., 11-verso
    - Taughannock Falls, 215 feet high, In the Finger Lakes region of central New York, 12
    - Verso: Taughannock Falls, the highest falls east of the Rocky Mts. [Mountains], in Taughannock State Park, located on Cayuga Lake near Ithaca, in the Finger Lakes Region of Central New York., 12-verso
    - Cloverbrook Farm, Pawling, N.Y., 13
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 13-verso
    - Cloverbook Farm, Pawling, N.Y., 14
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 14-verso
    - [The John Kane House, Washington's Headquarters during the fall of 1778. ], 15
    - Verso: The John Kane House, Washington's Headquarters, the fall of 1778. The Historical Society, Pawling, N.Y., 15-verso
    - Seasons Greetings; [Catamount Ski Area], 16
    - Verso: Catamount Ski Area, Hillsdale, New York], 16-verso
    - The Waldorf-Astoria-Bienuenida-The Welcome-by Jose Maria Sert, 17
    - Verso: The Waldorf-Astoria New York; "Bienuenida" - The Welcome. One of the fifteen murals depicting episodes selected from "The Marriage of Quiteria", as described by Cervants in chapters LVIII and LIX, in the second part of "Don Quixote". Paintings by Jose Maria Sert., 17-verso
    - The Waldort-Astoria-Sert Room-Murals by Jose Maria Sert, 18
    - Verso: The Waldorf-Astoria New York; The Sert Room-one of the Park Avenue Restaurants-contiental in atmosphere-cosmopolitain in patronage-named in honor of Jose Maria Sert, the distinguished Spanish painter whose murals adorn it - is a favorite restaurant of New York's most interesting people., 18-verso
    - The Waldorf-Astoria-The Silver Gallery, 19
    - Verso: The Waldorf-Astoria New York; The Ballroom Gallery-"The Silver Gallery". A gallery made of mirrors The piers are of matched harewood. Decorations and lighting fixtures are of silver and crystal Ceiling paintings by the American artist, Simmons. These were taken from the Astor Gallery in the former Waldorf-Astoria.], 19-verso
    - The Waldorf-Astoria-Basildon Room, 20
    - Verso: The Waldorf-Astoria New York; The Basildon Room. So called because it embodies features of rare historical and artistic interest reconstructed from a large 18th century living room taken from Basildon Park, Berkshire, England Included are modeled and painted cornices, fine paneling, a marbel amtel, attributed to John Flaxman, the sculptor, and oil paintings attributes to Angelica Kauffman., 20-verso
    - The Waldorf-Astoria-Norse Grill, 21
    - Verso: The Waldorf-Astoria New York; The Norse Grill. Massive stone arches combined with wooden beams and mouldings elaborately carved and colored in the Scandinavian manner The walls are of chestnut. Columns, pilasters, wainscoting, and mantelpiece are of French limestone...The map over the fireplace gives the location of golf clubs, and other sport centers in the vicinity of New York., 21-verso
    - The Waldorf-Astoria-Grand Ballroom, 22
    - Verso: The Waldorf-Astoria New York; The Grand Ballroom. The Grand Ballroom with its 12,000 feet of floor space and two tiers of boxes, together with other rooms on the third floor, provides banqueting space for more than 3,000 people and dancing space for 4,000...one of the finest pipe organs in the world is a feature of this room., 22-verso
    - The Waldorf-Astoria-Park Avenue Foyer-Murals by Louis Rigal, 23
    - Verso: The Waldorf-Astoria New York; The Park Avenue Foyer. A modern treatment with classic Pompeiian influence. Frieze painted by Louis Rigal who also designed the remarkable "Wheel of Life" Rug. The semi-indirect lighting comes from a marble panel in center of ceiling, and from eight urns arranged about the room., 23-verso
    - The Waldorf-Astoria-The Salon of a French Suite, 24
    - Verso: The Waldorf-Astoria New York; The Salon of a French Suite. Rooms are arranged so that one to four bedrooms may be added en suite. Black and white marble baths and boudoir dressing rooms add to the comfort and convenience of many of these suites. The individual treatment of each creates, in the manner of the luxurious private home, charm and comfort., 24-verso
    - Lake Mohonk House, Mohonk Lake, N.Y., 25
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 25-verso
    - [Lake Mohonk Mountain House and Lake], 26
    - Verso: Lake Mohonk Mountain House and Lake, from Sky Top, Mountain Lake, N.Y., 26-verso
    - [Christ Church on Quaker Hill, Pawling, New York], 27
    - Verso: Christ Church on Quaker Hill, Pawling, New York. An ecumenical congregation founded in 1895. Worship: 10:30 AM every Sunday of the yeat. Bernard Brunsting, Minisher Ralph Lankler, Minister Emeritus., 27-verso
    - Continental Avenue, showing Forest Hills Inn, Forest Hills, L.I., 28
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 28-verso
    - Garden Apartments, Forest Hills, L.I., 29
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 29-verso
  Box 1602
- Postcards, 2.1.7
  - United States of America (North Carolina), undated; 1 (Box 1602)
    - [Hotel Queen Anne in North Carolina], 1
    - Verso: Hotel Queen Anne, New Bern, North Carolina. Direction: Daniel M. Miles. View showing a portion of the Garden and Automobile Entrance., 1-verso
    - [Hotel Queen Anne in North Carolina], 2
    - Verso: Hotel Queen Anne, New Bern, North Carolina. Direction: Daniel M. Miles. View showing a portion of the Garden and Automobile Entrance., 2-verso
    - [Hotel Queen Anne, New Bern, North Carolina], 3
    - Verso: Hotel Queen Anne, New Bern, North Carolina. Direction: Daniel M. Miles. One of the Quiet and Cheerful Parlors enjoyed by the Guest., 3-verso
  - United States of America (Oregon), undated; 2 (Box 1602)
    - Shooting White Horse Rapids, Y.T., 1
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 1-verso
  - United States of America (Pennsylvania), undated; 3 (Box 1602)
    - Independence Hall, Chestnut St., Philidelphia, Pa. [Pennsylvania], 1